<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on HugoNest</title>
    <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on HugoNest</description>
    <image>
      <title>HugoNest</title>
      <url>https://hugonest.pages.dev/images/avatar.png</url>
      <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/images/avatar.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:14:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hugonest.pages.dev/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI for Bloggers: A Careful Balance</title>
      <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/posts/ai_for_bloggers_a_careful_balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugonest.pages.dev/posts/ai_for_bloggers_a_careful_balance/</guid>
      <description>This post discusses the author&amp;#39;s preference for using AI tools for tasks like content formatting and typo checking, while maintaining a focus on original, human-written content.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&rsquo;t like AI-generated content polluting my blog, but I really enjoy having AI help me with reformatting and checking for typos.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/posts/ai_for_bloggers_a_careful_balance/ai_opt.png"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HUGONEST Blog Enhancements: Navigation &amp; File Movement</title>
      <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/posts/hugonest_blog_enhancements_navigation__file_movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 15:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugonest.pages.dev/posts/hugonest_blog_enhancements_navigation__file_movement/</guid>
      <description>Updates to the HUGONEST blog, including seamless post navigation and the long-awaited ability to move files within the platform. Let us know what you think!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What&rsquo;s up, HUGONEST crew!</p>
<p>Another day, another round of code wrangling. Kept the momentum going today, focusing on smoothing out some core experiences within the app.</p>
<p>Today&rsquo;s big focus was on the blogging features. Specifically, I implemented navigation between blog posts. You know, the classic &ldquo;Next Post&rdquo; / &ldquo;Previous Post&rdquo; links you see everywhere? Yep, HUGONEST has that now! Should make browsing through content a whole lot easier and keep people engaged without having to jump back to an index page constantly. Small change, big usability win (I hope!).
<img loading="lazy" src="/posts/hugonest_blog_enhancements_navigation__file_movement/cut.png"></p>
<p>On top of that, I circled back to the file management side of things. Remember how you could upload and view files? Well, now you can actually MOVE them! 🎉 It sounds basic, but it&rsquo;s a crucial step for proper organization. No more clunky workarounds if you decide a file belongs in a different folder. Just drag it (or, well, use the &lsquo;move&rsquo; command) and boom, it&rsquo;s there. Still more to do on the file manager, but this felt like a necessary piece to get in place.
<img loading="lazy" src="/posts/hugonest_blog_enhancements_navigation__file_movement/cut2.png"></p>
<p>Making steady progress and ticking things off the list! Always feels good.</p>
<p>As always, I&rsquo;m building this out in the open, so your feedback is gold. How&rsquo;s the blog experience shaping up for you? Any specific file management tools you&rsquo;re hoping for next? Hit me up in the comments!</p>
<p>Cheers</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
