<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown Challenges on HugoNest</title>
    <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/tags/markdown-challenges/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Markdown Challenges on HugoNest</description>
    <image>
      <title>HugoNest</title>
      <url>https://hugonest.pages.dev/images/avatar.png</url>
      <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/images/avatar.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 10:09:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hugonest.pages.dev/tags/markdown-challenges/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing Hugo/Jekyll Blogs on Mobile: Markdown Syntax Woes</title>
      <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/posts/202504/writing_hugo_jekyll_blogs_on_mobile_markdown_syntax_woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 10:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugonest.pages.dev/posts/202504/writing_hugo_jekyll_blogs_on_mobile_markdown_syntax_woes/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the challenges of writing blog posts on mobile devices for Hugo/Jekyll sites, with a focus on Markdown syntax difficulties and a solution using AI.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey folks,</p>
<p>So I&rsquo;ve been messing around with writing blog posts for my Hugo/Jekyll site directly on my phone sometimes. And whenever this topic comes up, you always hear about the Markdown editor being clunky, or wrestling with getting changes synced and committed via Git on mobile.</p>
<p>And yeah, those <em>can</em> be annoying, but honestly? That&rsquo;s not the <em>main</em> headache for me.</p>
<p>The absolute worst part, the thing that <em>really</em> makes it a pain, is trying to wrestle with all that Markdown syntax on that little phone keyboard. Especially when you need to drop in an image or a link.</p>
<p>Trying to type out <code>![alt text](image-url.jpg)</code> or <code>[link text](http://url.com)</code> with all the brackets, parentheses, finding the right keys, making sure the syntax is <em>just right</em>&hellip; it totally breaks my flow. I feel like I&rsquo;m doing surgery on a postage stamp. It&rsquo;s so hard to just type freely and quickly when you have to constantly stop and think about formatting syntax.</p>
<p>What I <em>really</em> wish I could do is just type naturally, like I&rsquo;m sending a text to a friend. Just get my thoughts down without caring about strict Markdown rules in the moment.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s my thought: What if I could just dump my plain text draft into something (an app? a tool?), and then hit a button, and some smart AI figures out where the links/images should go based on context or simple cues, and formats it into correct Markdown?</p>
<p>Like, the AI <em>only</em> does the formatting. It doesn&rsquo;t write the content at all. It just takes my free-form text and adds the <code>[]()</code>, <code>#</code>, <code>*</code>, etc., where they belong.</p>
<p>Does anyone else struggle with this specific part of mobile static site writing? Am I missing some obvious trick? What are your workflows?</p>
<p>Curious to hear your thoughts!</p>
<p>UPDATE: So, I actually found something that seems to do exactly this! It&rsquo;s called <a href="https://hugonest.github.io/">HugoNest</a>  It lets me just type naturally on my phone without worrying about the exact Markdown syntax, and then it uses AI to handle the formatting automatically afterwards. This seriously feels like it solves the main pain point I was having. Just wanted to share in case anyone else felt the same way!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
