<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on HugoNest</title>
    <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on HugoNest</description>
    <image>
      <title>HugoNest</title>
      <url>https://hugonest.pages.dev/images/avatar.png</url>
      <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/images/avatar.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 10:31:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hugonest.pages.dev/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Mobile Management: Need Your Help Testing Our New Android App</title>
      <link>https://hugonest.pages.dev/posts/202504/hugo_mobile_management_need_your_help_testing_our_new_android_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 10:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hugonest.pages.dev/posts/202504/hugo_mobile_management_need_your_help_testing_our_new_android_app/</guid>
      <description>A tool in development to simplify Hugo blog management on mobile devices.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone!</p>
<p>If you use Hugo for your blog, like me, and sometimes wish it was easier to do simple things on your phone, then maybe you&rsquo;ll find this interesting.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been working on a small tool that I hope will help Hugo users manage their blogs easier on their phones. Right now, it&rsquo;s in the very early testing stages, but I think some of you might like the idea.</p>
<p>Basically, this tool (let&rsquo;s call it HugoNest for now) wants to make it simpler to manage your Hugo blog on your phone, so you don&rsquo;t always need a computer. It can do a few basic things like:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Work on different phones and computers.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Help with simple Git stuff.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Make it easier to write in Markdown on your phone.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Have some new AI features to help you write.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Make it easy to add pictures from your phone.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Show changes in the app quickly.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>I know that for a tool like Hugo, being stable and keeping your data safe is super important. That&rsquo;s why I&rsquo;ve thought about these things from the start (like keeping your keys safe on your phone).</p>
<p>Right now, I&rsquo;m doing a small test with a few people. I&rsquo;d really like to get some real feedback to help make this tool better. If you also use Hugo and are willing to spend a little time trying out this early version and give me your thoughts, I would really appreciate it!</p>
<p>As a thank you for helping me test, if you join our early testing group, you will <strong>get to use this app for free.</strong></p>
<p><strong>If you&rsquo;re interested in joining the test, please send me an email or a message with your email address.</strong> I will use your email to add you to the list of testers on Google Play.</p>
<p>My email address is:  <a href="mailto:HugoNest@xgdebug.com">HugoNest@xgdebug.com</a></p>
<p>I&rsquo;m really excited to see how we can make using Hugo even better together!</p>
<p>Thanks a lot!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://hugonest.github.io/static/media/dashboard.png"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
